Guide to the Albert Jay Nock Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Albert Jay Nock papers
1892-1969
MS 375
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(8 boxes)
Correspondence and writings of Albert Jay Nock, author and editor. Also included are writings and correspondence about Nock (mainly materials collected by Robert Crunden for his book on Nock, The Mind and Art of Albert Jay Nock, Chicago, 1964), and materials concerning Ruth Robinson, a close friend of Nock; in fact, the larger part of the collection consists of correspondence between Nock and Miss Robinson. Important correspondents include H. L. Mencken, Ellery Sedgwick, Brand Whitlock, Newton D. Baker, Jacques Barzun, Lewis Mumford, and John Dos Passos.
Nock, Albert Jay, 1872 or 1873-1945
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Paul Palmer, Robert Crunden, and Ruth Robinson.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. Ruth Robinson. II. Paul Palmer. III. Robert M. Crunden.
Scope and Contents
The Albert Jay Nock Collection consists of the correspondence and writings of Albert Jay Nock, correspondence and writings of others about Nock, and some materials concerning Ruth Robinson, an intimate friend of Nock's. Much of the correspondence and writings is unpublished.
The collection is arranged into three series, under the name of the person who collected and donated the papers.
Series I, "Ruth Robinson," is the largest series in the collection and consists primarily of letters from Nock to Ruth Robinson. The series also includes letters to Nock from H. L. Mencken, Ellery Sedgwick, Brand Whitlock, Newton Baker, and Senator Robert Wagner.
Series II, "Paul Palmer," was originally part of the Paul Palmer Papers, (See: Paul Palmer Papers, Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University.) Palmer, who, like Nock, was a member of the Players' Club in New York, was the editor of The Mercury for which Nock wrote articles and the Reader's Digest. Among the notable correspondents in this series are Lawrence R. Abbott, Rutger B. Jewett, and Brand Whitlock.
Series III, "Robert M. Crunden," Consists of papers collected by Crunden for a thesis he wrote as an undergraduate at Yale University, which was later published as a book, The Mind and Art of Albert Jay Nock (Chicago: Henry Regnery Co., 1964). There is also a group of letters to Crunden from people who knew Nock. Notable correspondents in this group include: Harry Elmer Barnes, Jacques Barzun, John Dos Passos, Margaret Storrs Grierson, Hugh Mac Carran, Lewis Mumford, and Edmund A. Opitz.
* For additional Nock papers see the Richard E. Danielson Papers and the Charles Nagel Papers, Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Biographical / Historical
Albert Jay Nock was a fiercely private man; biographical information is scarce indeed. He was born October 13, 1870 in Scranton, Pennsylvania. (Nock himself claimed 1873 or, maybe 1874 as the year of his birth; it was, he thought, a matter of little consequence). His father, Joseph Albert Nock, was a clergyman in the Protestant Episcopal Church; his mother, Emma Sheldon Jay, was a descendant of the Rochellois Protestants who arrived in America in the late 1680's. Much of Nock's youth was spent in Alpena, Michigan, where his father had established a church.
Nock attended St. Stephen's College (now Bard College) at Annandale-on-Hudson, New York, from which he received an A.B. degree in 1892. Evidence of Nock's activities between 1892 and 1898 are fragmentary at best. It appears that he took some graduate courses at the Berkeley Divinity School., which was then in Middletown, Connecticut. In any event, he was ordained to the ministry of the Episcopal Church in 1897 and was called to St. James Church, Titusville, Pennsylvania the following year. In Titusville, he met Agnes Grumbine (1876-1935), who he married on April 25, 1900. The marriage produced two sons, Francis Jay and Samuel Albert, but during the time Ruth Robinson knew him (from 1909 until his death in 1945), Nock rarely saw or mentioned his family.
Nock left the active ministry late in 1909 to join the staff of American Magazine, where he proved his skill in editing as well as writing. In 1915 Crowell bought American Magazine and turned it into a popular magazine. Nock then joined the staff of the Nation, where his name appeared on the mast-head as an associate editor from July 27, 1918 to November 29, 1919. He left the Nation for the famous Freeman, which he co-edited, with Francis Neilson the British single-taxer, from 1920 until it ceased publication in 1924. By that time Nock was weary of editorial duties and never again accepted a regular editorial position. Instead, he devoted the rest of his life to travels and writing.
Nock was a fierce champion of individualism and it is this credo which spurred his attacks on social and political institutions. In an autobiographical sketch he prepared for Paul Palmer, Nock wrote: "Responsibility to myself and for myself, yes. I am, as I have always been, proud to accept that, proud to assert it in the face of God, man, beast, or devil. But responsibility for anything beyond that I accept only on the strength of the most searching evidence; and I have a peculiarily resolute resentment against the impositions by State, Church, or social conventions of responsibilities which are purely aritificial in substance and fraudulent in intention."
Nock was early associated with progressivism, but by the end of World War I he found himself labeled a conservative, a name he at first resisted, but finally accepted and defended until the end of his life. In fact, Nock was never really a reformer for he viewed attempts at conversion as a violation of the individual integrity of others. Similarly, he was pessimistic about the possibility of social change. True change, he believed, must be an aggregate of the voluntary changes in individuals.
In addition to several volumes of collected essays, Nock's works include: Jefferson, a biography (1926), Francis Rabelais (1929), A Journey into Rabelais's France (1934), A Journal of These Days (1934), Our Enemy the State (1935), Free Speech and Plain Language (1937), and Henry George (1939). Nock's best-received book was his autobiography, Memoirs of a Superfluous Man(1943).
* For additional biographical information, see The Superflous Anarchist: Albert Jay Nock, by Michel Wreszin (Providence, R. I.: Brown University Press, 1972).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Journalism; Diaries; Authors; Editors; Journalists; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937; Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1889-1968; Barzun, Jacques, 1907-2012; Chodorov, Frank, 1887-1966; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990; Nock, Albert Jay, 1872 or 1873-1945; Opitz, Edmund A., 1914-; Palmer, Ruth; Robinson, Ruth; Sedgwick, Ellery, 1872-1960; Whitlock, Brand, 1869-1934
- RUTH ROBINSON, 1910-1969; Series I; 2' (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials collected and donated by Ruth Robinson and is divided into two subsections: "Correspondence" and "Special Files."
  The bulk of the correspondence consists of letters to and from Nock, most of which are letters from Nock to Ruth Robinson. Letters are arranged alphabetically by the name of Nock's correspondent and chronologically within each folder. Typed copies of Nock's letters made by Ruth Robinson are filed immediately after the original letter. In addition, Robinson wrote editorial footnotes to the letters clarifying or elaborating upon unclear references. These will be found at the end of the correspondence. Numbers appearing on the typed copies of the letters mark the footnoted passages. Recording tapes used to make the typed copies of Nock's letters follow the editorial footnotes.
  There is a small section of correspondence by various persons addressed to Ruth Robinson or to Nock's sons, which were written after Nock's death. Most of these letters deal with the publication of Selected Letters of Albert Jay Nock or are about various writings about Nock. Among the correspondents in this section are: Bernard Iddings Bell, William Harlowe Briggs, Frank Chodorov, George Libaire, Robert M. Thornton, and Nock's two sons, Francis Jay and Samuel Albert Nock.
  "Special Files" consists of two published articles by Nock; the November, 1944 issue of Encore, for which Nock was the guest editor; printed materials about Nock and his writings; photos and autobiographical notes by Ruth Robinson; and some of the original pen and ink drawings done by Robinson for Nock's Journey into Rabelais's France. In addition, there are printed materials about the publication of The Freeman, guest lists, and programs for dramatic productions by the Player's Club, of which Nock was a member.
  - Correspondence
    - Atlantic Monthly (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General
      See also: box 3, folder 46
    - American Magazine (Box 1, Folder 2)
      See also: box 3, folder 47
    - Baker, Newton D, (Mayor of Cleveland) 1915. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Darrow, Karl K. 31 December, 1943. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Encore (Box 1, Folder 5)
      See also: box 3, folder 48
    - Hobson, Henry 1939. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Johnston, Sir Harry H. 1924. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mencken, H. L. 3 May, 1913. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Morrow, William, and Company (Box 1, Folder 9)
      See also: box 1, folder 6
    - Parsons, Louis A. "Zebe," 1943. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Reese, Daniel Hawes 1913. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1910, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1911, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1912, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1913, January-April, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1913, May-June, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1913, July-August, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1913, September-October, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1913, November-December, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1914, January-April, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1914, May-August, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1914, September-December, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1915, January-June, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 1915, July-December, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 1916, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 1917, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - 1919, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - 1921, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - 1922, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - 1923, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - 1924, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - 1925, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - 1926, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - 1927, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - 1928, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - 1930, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - 1931-1933, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - 1934, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - 1935, 1937, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 1938, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 1939, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - 1940-1942, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - 1943, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - 1944-1945, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Postcards--no dates--to Ruth Robinson. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Sedgwick, Ellery (Ed. of AtlanticMonthly ), 1915, 1930, 1931. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Siddall, John, assoc. editor, American Magazine, May, 1913. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Smith, Dent, editor of Encore; letter congratulating Nock's editing of November, 1944, issue--8 November, 1944. (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Wagner, Sen. Robert F.. Undated. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Whitlock, Brand "Mawruss," 1912, 1913. (Box 3, Folder 50)
      See also: box 1, folder 3
    - Wilson, Catherine Rose, 9 September, 1933. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Ruth Robinson's editorial footnotes to A. J. Nock's letters (all the preceding material). (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Tape made by Ruth Robinson used to correct the type-script and make notes for the collection of typescript copies of letters of A. J. Nock to Ruth Robinson. Reel # 1. (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Tape made by Ruth Robinson used to correct the typescript and make notes for the collection of typescript copies of letters of A. J. Nock to Ruth Robinson. Reel # 2. (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Tape made by Ruth Robinson used to correct the typescript and make notes for the collection of typescript copies of letters of A. J. Nock to Ruth Robinson. Reel # 3. (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Tape made by Ruth Robinson used to correct the typescript and make notes for the collection of typescript copies of letters of A. J. Nock to Ruth Robinson. Reel # 4. (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Bell, Bernard Iddings, minister, to: Samuel A. Nock, August 22, 1945 and to Ruth Robinson 23 August, 1945. (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Briggs, William Harlow (Harper Bros.) to Ruth Robinson 1945-1946, 1950, 1951. (Box 4, Folder 58)
      See also: box 4, folder 71
    - Briggs, William Harlow (Harper Bros.) to Catherine R. Wilson 1946. (Box 4, Folder 59)
      See also: box 6, folder 8
    - Caxton Printers, Ltd. (J. H. Gipson, president) to Ruth Robinson 1961. (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Caxton Printers (J. H. Gipson, pres.) to Robert M. Thornton 1 November, 1960. (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Chodorov, Frank to Ruth Robinson August 26, 1946. (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Clough, Benjamin Crocker to Ruth Robinson September, 1962. (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Colcord, Lincoln to Ruth Robinson May 12, 1946. (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Cziraky, Sandor, to Ernest von Harringa; 10 October, 1958. (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Cziraky, Sandor to Ruth Robinson (letters concerning dissertation on AJN) 1958-1962. (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Gipson, J. H., president, Caxton Printers, to Ruth Robinson. (Box 4, Folder 67)
      See also: box 4, folder 60
    - Harper & Brothers, Publishers. (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Libaire, George to Ruth Robinson, 22 August, 1946; and to Frank Chodorov 21 August, 1946. (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Nock, Francis to Ruth Robinson, 1945-1947, 1951, 1956, and undated. (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Nock, Samuel A.; letters to/from Briggs, William Harlowe, 1946 and 1950. (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Nock, Samuel A.; to Mrs. Edward Nicholas, 1 September, 1945, and Ellen Winsor, 15 February, 1957. (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Nock, Samuel A. to Ruth Robinson, 19 August, 1945-1913 January, 1950; 25 May, 1955-1912 February, 1957. (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Thornton, Robert M. to Ruth Robinson, 21 July, 1959-1919 December, 1961. (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (mostly to Ruth Robinson) concerning AJN's death and later publication of his works. (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Special Files (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - "Advertising and Liberal Literature," from The Sewanee Review (date unknown) by Albert Jay Nock. (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - "Anarchist's Progress," from Analysis, November, 1949, by Albert Jay Nock. (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Encore, vol. VI, no. 33, Nov., 1944; Albert Jay Nock, guest editor. (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Analysis, vol. II, no. 10, August, 1946, memorial issue on Albert Jay Nock. (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Fragments, memorial issue, April-June, 1966. Articles by and about Albert Jay Nock. (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Clippings and reviews, miscellaneous, concerning Nock and his works. (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Reed, John, The Day in Bohemia, or Life Among the Artists, excerpts mentioning Nock, 1913. (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Robinson, Ruth, autobiographical notes of 1965, 1969 (containing information about Nock). (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Robinson, Ruth, a few of the drawings for A Journey into Rabelais' France (text by A. J. Nock). (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Robinson, Ruth, photos of. (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Freeman, Huebsch's announcement of his intention to publish; vol. 1, no. 1, March 17, 1920; and The Freeman, Jr., (parody) vol. 1, no. 1/2, Mar. 5, 1925. (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Freeman, birthday dinners for, invitations, address lists, and letters of acceptance or rejection. (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Freeman, brief note concerning doctoral dissertation on, author unknown (in handwriting of Ruth Robinson). (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - The Players, programs for productions by; 1922, 1923, 1924, 1927. (Box 5, Folder 89)
- PAUL PALMER, 1911-1945, 1946; Series II; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  This series contains materials collected and donated by Paul Palmer, Nock's friend and associate. The series is divided into three subsections: "Correspondence," "Writings," and "Printed Matter."
  "Correspondence" is arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent and chronologically within each folder. Approximately half of this section consists of correspondence between Palmer and Nock; the remainder, with the exception of two third-party letters, one addressed to Ruth Robinson and the other to Palmer, are letters from various people to Nock.
  "Writings" contains manuscripts by Nock, both published and unpublished, and printed articles by Nock, some of which are unsigned. The manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by subject (most do not have titles); the printed articles are arranged alphabetically by title, or, if untitled, by type, e.g., reviews.
  "Printed Matter" contains published material about Nock and his writings and is arranged alphabetically by type. Photographs of Nock are included in this section.
  - Correspondence
    - Abbott, Lawrence F. ( The Outlook ), June, 1913. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Appleton, D., & Co. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      See also: box 6, folder 13
    - Atlantic Monthly, editor ("Teu") to Palmer, Paul, senior editor, Readers Digest, 24 August, 1948. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Atlantic Monthly. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      See also: box 6, folder 28
    - "A. A. B." ( American Magazine ) 1914, 1915, and undated. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Bell, Bernard Iddings, 26 September, 1934. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Boyden, A., undated. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Briggs, William Harlowe (Harper & Brothers, Publishers) 7 November, 1941. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Cary, William B., minister, 11 September, 1918. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Harper & Brothers, Publishers. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Hazard, Caroline to Ruth Robinson, 11 September, 1934. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hobson, Thayer (William Morrow & Co., Publishers), 28 October, 1933. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Jewett, Rutger B. (D. Appleton & Co.) concerning AJN's introduction to book by B. Whitlock, December, 1913. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Johnston, Sir Henry H., 27 March, 1924. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Kennedy, Charles W., 24 March, 1911. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - McCurdy, Allen W., minister, 28 April, 1913. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Morningside Presbyterian Church. (Box 6, Folder 17)
      See also: box 6, folder 16
    - Morrow, William, & Co., Publishers. (Box 6, Folder 18)
      See also: box 6, folder 12 box 6, folder 27
    - The Outlook. (Box 6, Folder 19)
      See also: box 6, folder 1
    - Palmer, Paul (from A. J. Nock), 1937-1938. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Palmer, Paul (to A. J. Nock), 1938. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Palmer, Paul (from A. J. Nock), 1939-1940. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Palmer, Paul (from A. J. Nock), 1941-1942. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Palmer, Paul (to A. J. Nock), 6 November, 1941. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Palmer, Paul (from A. J. Nock), 1943. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Palmer, Paul (from A. J. Nock), 1944-1945 and undated. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Phillips, Frances (William Morrow & Co., publishers), 30 October, 1933. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Sedgwick, Ellery, editor, The Atlantic Monthly, 1914, 1934. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Thompson, Maud, re: "Motherhood and the State" by AJN in Atlantic Monthly, July, 1914; August, 1914. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Van Loon, Hendrick Willens, 5 October, 1934. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Whitlock, Brand, 1912 and undated. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Anonymous admirer of "Motherhood and the State" by AJN, Atlantic Monthly, July, 1914. (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Writings
    - MS. of autobiographical memoir by A. J. Nock for use by Paul Palmer. (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - MS. (typed) of"In the Interpreter's House," by A. J. Nock, undated, re: The abasement of Christmas. (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - MS. of introduction by A. J. Nock to book by Brand Whitlock (?), 20 November, 1913. (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - MS. of article on liberalism, by A. J. Nock. (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - MS. (typed) of unpublished journal of travels in Europe, by A. J. Nock, 5 May, 1934--25 January, 1935; 10 August (1935?)--27 October (1935?). (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - MS. (typed) of account of travels in France, by A. J. Nock. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - "About a Book or Two," by A. J. Nock, from Analysis, July, 1945. (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Address to Classical Conference by A. J. Nock (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - "American Indifference to Affairs of Government Is Largely Due to Our Unwieldy Political System," by A. J. Nock. Reprinted in the Providence, Rhode Island, Bulletin, Feb. 8, 1933. (Originally printed in The American Mercury ). (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - "Anarchist's Progress," by A. J. Nock. reprinted from Analysis. (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - "Basis of Government," an outline by A. J. Nock in Nock's handwriting. (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - "A Canadian Railway's Public Spirit" and "Radical Wisdom," by A. J. Nock from The Outlook; "This Week," 10 May, 1913, pp. 43-44. (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - "Democracy Here and Abroad," by A. J. Nock from The New York Evening Post, 30 January, 1918. (Newspaper clipping and typed copy). (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - "An Extraordinary Correspondence," galley proofs (from American Magazine ?) (by A. J. Nock?) (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Frank Gilbreth's Great Plan to Introduce Time-Study into Surgery or "Efficiency and the High-Brow"--fragment, The American Magazine, p. 48, undated, by A. J. Nock. (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - "The Instinct for Style," from The Nation, 24 May 1919, pp. 824-825. (by A. J. Nock?) (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," from The American Magazine, March, 1912, pp. 635-640. (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," from The American Magazine, April, 1912, pp. 766-768. (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," from The American Magazine, June, 1912, pp. 243-256. (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," (by A. J. Nock?) [re:] Czar Nicholas II of Russia; Galley Proofs from The American Magazine (Dec. 4, 1912?). (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," (by A. J. Nock?) [re:] scientific management; Galley Proofs from The American Magazine, undated. (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," from The American Magazine, undated, pp. 94-97, [re:] baseball (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," from The American Magazine, undated, pp. 132-137, [re:] Christianity and industrial autocracy (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," [re:] the liberals; from The American Magazine, pp. 122-131, undated (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," from The American Magazine, undated, pp. 92-95, [re:] movies (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - "In the Interpreter's House," from The American Magazine, undated, pp. 92-97, [re:] railroads (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - In the Interpreter's House--fragments from The American Magazine, undated (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - "In Time of Need," from The Nation, June 7, 1919, p. 905 (by A. J. Nock?). (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - "Isaiah's Job," by A. J. Nock, extracted from Ch. 13 of Free Speech and Plain Language, by A. J. Nock (1937). Reprinted as vol. 9, no. 3 of In Brief, by The Foundation for Economic Education, Inc. (October, 1952). (Box 7, Folder 61)